Guide to the Carlyle Marney Papers, 1899-1979 RL.00848
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Speeches Series, 1930-1978 and undated
  - Writings by Carlyle Marney
    - Faith and the Falcon, lecture draft, 1950s (Box 148)
      This long draft (26 pages) includes as sub-sections two lectures/sermons given on KTBC-TV: "The Hills of Home," Dec. 10, 1954, and "Grandmother Asia," Feb. 4, 1955. The lecture as a whole speaks mainly to how prejudices are formed and negative impacts on modern societies.
    - Book Reviews, 1959-1968 undated (Box 65)
    - Beggars in Velvet, 1960 (4 folders and 1 volume) (Box 1960)
    - 1961 (Box 66)
    - Structures of Prejudice: Lectures prepared for Meredith College School of Christian Studies, Raleigh, N.C., 1955 June 13-17 (Box 148)
      Includes laid-in correspondence (three pages) dated May 24, 1961, addressed by Marney to "Bud," on his reaction to Marney's writing, "Structures of Prejudice." Housed in original ring binder with soft leather covers, stamped "Carlyle Marney."
    - Structures of Prejudice (Notes), 1961, 4 folders (Box 66)
    - Structures of Prejudice, 1961, 2 folders (Box 67)
    - Structures of Prejudice (Revised), 1961, 2 folders (Box 67)
    - Structures of Prejudice (Rejected copy), 1961 (Box 67)
    - Structures of Prejudice (Correction copy), 1961 (Box 67)
    - Structures of Prejudice (Copy 2 and index), 1961, 5 folders (Box 68)
    - Structures of Prejudice (Miscellaneous), 1961 (Box 68)
    - Structures of Prejudice (Reviews), 1960-1964) (Box 68)
    - Structures of Prejudice (Correspondence), 1961 (Box 68)
    - Structures of Prejudice (Gift copies), 1961 (Box 68)
    - 1962-1963, 4 folders (Box 69)
    - Recovery of the Person, 1963 (Box 69)
    - 1964, Jan.- May (Box 69)
    - 1964, June-Dec., 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Christian Community and the Homosexual, 1964 (Box 70)
    - Dayton's Long Hot Summer (Scopes Trial), 1964 (Box 70)
    - He Became Like Us, 1964 (Box 70)
    - 1965, 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Let Us Keep Christmas, 1965 (Box 70)
    - 1966-1967, 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Carpenter's Son, 1967, 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Carpenter's Son (Correspondence), 1967 (Box 71)
    - Carpenter's Son (Reviews), 1967 (Box 71)
    - 1968-1970 (Box 71)
    - The Coming Faith, 1970 (Box 71)
    - 1972, Jan.-1974 Mar. (Box 72)
    - Dickson Lectures, 1974, Apr.-Dec. (Box 72)
    - Priests to Each Other, 1974 (Box 72)
    - 1975 (Box 72)
    - VMI Handwritten Lectures, 1976, Jan.-Feb. (Box 72)
    - VMI Typed Lectures, 1976, Jan-Feb. (Box 73)
    - 1976, Mar.-1978, Mar. (Box 73)
    - Undated Writings:
      - A, undated (Box 73)
      - Acts: A Series on the Book of Acts, undated (Box 73)
      - Austin Lectures, undated (Box 73)
      - B-E, undated, 2 folders (Box 73)
      - Ecclesiology in the Early Church (unpublished), undated (Box 73)
      - Ecclesiology in the Early Church (unpublished), undated, 2 folders (Box 74)
      - F-G, undated (Box 74)
      - Genesis, undated (Box 74)
      - H-P, undated, 3 folders (Box 74)
      - The Preparation (unpublished), undated (Box 74)
      - R. undated (Box 74)
      - The Recovery of the Church (unpublished), undated, 3 folders (Box 75)
      - The Rise of Ecclesiological Externalism, undated, 3 folders (Box 75)
      - S-T, undated, 2 folders (Box 76)
      - Television Programs, undated, 3 folders (Box 76)
      - U-Z, undated (Box 76)
      - No title, undated (Box 76)
    - A Series of Sermons Delivered by Dr. Carlyle Marney...at First Baptist Church, Florence, Alabama, October 2-7, 1960 (Box 148)
      Titles of sermons include: A Man Must Kneel; The Moment Before God; and The Recovery of Courage. Topics include moral blindness, religious timidity and apathy, and, more obliquely, southern society.
  - Writings by Others
    - A, Miscellaneous, 1959-1966 (Box 77)
    - Alexander, John Stanley, 1971 and undated (Box 77)
    - B. Miscellaneous, 1957-1975, 2 folders (Box 77)
    - Baker, William J., 1970-1973 (Box 77)
    - Barnette, H.H., 1943-1944 (Box 77)
    - Broach, Claude U., 1962 and undated (Box 77)
    - Brokhoff, Dr. J.R., 1960- 1962 (Box 77)
    - Brown, Glen J., Jr., 1965-1966 and undated (Box 77)
    - C, Miscellaneous, 1954-1978 (Box 78)
    - Carr, Warren, 1963 (Box 78)
    - Clark, Theodore R., undated (Box 78)
    - D, Miscellaneous, 1956-1968 (Box 78)
    - Davis, W.H. (William Hershel), 1930 (Box 78)
    - Dyal, Robert A., 1960-1961 and undated (Box 78)
    - E, Miscellaneous, 1949-1961 (Box 78)
    - Evans, Bruce, 1964-1966 and undated (Box 78)
    - F. Miscellaneous, 1950-1972 (Box 78)
    - Fuller, Dr., 1950 (Box 78)
    - G. Miscellaneous, 1964-1966 and undated (Box 79)
    - Gilmour, MacLean, 1957-1960 and undated (Box 79)
    - Ginascol, Frederick H., 1955-1960 (Box 79)
    - H. Miscellaneous, 1959-1978 (Box 79)
    - Harris, Rufus Carrollton, 1960-1966 and undated (Box 79)
    - Heaton, George D., undated (Box 79)
    - Hilddreth, Lory, undated (Box 79)
    - Hill, Samuel S., Jr., 1966 (Box 79)
    - Inzer, John W., undated, 2 folders (Box 79)
    - J. Miscellaneous, 1963-1971 (Box 80)
    - K, Miscellaneous, 1961-1973 (Box 80)
    - Kerley, William C., 1971-1973 (Box 80)
    - Kilgore, William Jackson, 1959-1969 and undated (Box 80)
    - Kliever, Lonnie D., 1960 and undated (Box 80)
    - L, Miscellaneous, 1946-1961 (Box 80)
    - Littell, Franklin Hamlin, 1959-1966 (Box 80)
    - M, Miscellaneous, 1954-1973, 2 folders (Box 81)
    - Macdonald, Murdo Ewen, 1969 (Box 81)
    - Maguire, John David, 1969 and undated (Box 81)
    - McClernon, Robert E., 1961 (Box 81)
    - Mead, Lauren B., 1972 (Box 81)
    - Menninger, Karl, 1972 (Chapters 5-9) (Box 81)
    - Menninger, Karl, 1973 (Chapters 10-11) (Box 82)
    - Mikolaski, Samuel J., 1963-1966 and undated (Box 82)
    - Mondy, Robert William, 1950, 2 folders (Box 82)
    - Moody, E.B., undated (Box 82)
    - Mowrer, Orval Hobart., 1961-1962 and undated (Box 82)
    - Murphy, Arthur E., 1926-1963 (Box 82)
    - N. Miscellaneous, 1956-1961 (Box 83)
    - Newelt, Hans, undated (Box 83)
    - Niebuhr, H. Richard, 1946-1947 (Box 83)
    - O. Miscellaneous, 1960-1962 (Box 83)
    - Ogden, Schubert Miles, undated (Box 83)
    - P. Miscellaneous, 1954-1976 (Box 83)
    - Price, Theron D., 1957-1977 and undated (Box 83)
    - R. Miscellaneous, 1944-1978 (Box 83)
    - Ranson, Guy Harvey, 1944-1960 and n.d, 2 folders (Box 83)
    - S. Miscellaneous, 1961-1977, 2 folders (Box 84)
    - St.Amant, Clyde Penrose, 1955 (Box 84)
    - Skoglund, John Egnar, undated (Box 84)
    - Smith, Blake, 1959-1960 (Box 84)
    - Southard, Samuel, undated (Box 84)
    - Stembridge, Jane, 1977 (Box 84)
    - Stuart, J. Kenneth, 1974-1975 (Box 84)
    - Sumner, Lee (?), undated (Box 85)
    - T. Miscellaneous, 1954-1973 (Box 85)
    - Tracy, Nat, 1964-1965 and undated (Box 85)
    - V, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 85)
    - W. Miscellaneous, 1954-1973 (Box 85)
    - Ward, Jim, 1968 (Box 85)
    - Weatherspoon, J.B., 1943-1961 (Box 85)
    - Williamson, George, Jr., 1974-1975 (Box 85)
    - Y. Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 86)
    - Z. Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 86)
    - Anonymous, 1942-1976 and undated, 3 folders (Box 86)
- Engagement Files Series, 1958-1978
  Chiefly correspondence organized by the date of the speaking appointment; papers for each appointment are then filed chronologically. Grouped together at the end of most years are invitations declined and engagements pending or completed for that year.
  - 1958, June-1959, Dec., 8 folders (Box 87)
  - 1960, Jan.-Dec., 6 folders (Box 88)
  - 1961, Jan.-Dec., 7 folders (Box 89)
  - Engagements Pending, 1961 (Box 90)
  - Engagements Declined, 1961, 2 folders (Box 90)
  - 1962, July-Dec., 4 folders (Box 91)
  - Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 91)
  - Engagements Declined, 1962 (Box 91)
  - 1963, Jan.-Aug., 5 folders (Box 92)
  - 1963, Sept.-Dec., 3 folders (Box 93)
  - Engagements Declined, 1963 (Box 93)
  - Engagements Pending, 1963 (Box 93)
  - 1964, Jan.-June, 3 folders (Box 93)
  - 1964, July-Dec., 2 folders (Box 94)
  - Engagements Pending, 1964 (Box 94)
  - Engagements Declined, 1964 (Box 94)
  - 1965, Jan.-Mar. (Box 94)
  - 1965, Apr.-Dec., 3 folders (Box 95)
  - Engagements Pending, 1965 (Box 95)
  - Engagements Declined, 1965 (Box 95)
  - Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 95)
  - 1966, Jan.-Mar. (Box 95)
  - 1966, Apr.-Dec., 2 folders (Box 96)
  - Engagements Pending, 1966 (Box 96)
  - Engagements Declined, 1966 (Box 96)
  - Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 96)
  - 1967, Jan.-Dec., 3 folders (Box 96)
  - Engagements Pending, 1967 (Box 97)
  - Engagements Declined, 1967 (Box 97)
  - 1968, Jan.-Aug., 3 folders (Box 97)
  - 1968, Sept.-Dec., 2 folders (Box 98)
  - Engagements Pending, 1968 (Box 98)
  - Engagements Declined, 1969 (Box 98)
  - 1969, Jan.-May, 2 folders (Box 98)
  - 1969, June-Dec., 2 folders (Box 99)
  - Engagements Pending, 1969 (Box 99)
  - Engagements Declined, 1969 (Box 99)
  - 1970, Jan.-Apr. (Box 99)
  - 1970, May-Dec., 2 folders (Box 100)
  - Engagements Pending, 1970 (Box 100)
  - Engagements Declined, 1970 (Box 100)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 100)
  - 1971, Jan.-July, 2 folders (Box 100)
  - 1971, Aug.-Dec. (Box 101)
  - Engagements Pending, 1971 (Box 101)
  - Engagements Declined, 1971 (Box 101)
  - 1972, Jan.-Sept., 3 folders (Box 101)
  - 1972, Oct.-Dec. (Box 102)
  - Engagements Pending, 1972 (Box 102)
  - Engagements Declined, 1972 (Box 102)
  - 1973, Jan.-Sept., 4 folders (Box 102)
  - 1973, Oct.-Dec., 2 folders (Box 103)
  - Engagements Pending, 1973 (Box 103)
  - Engagements Declined, 1973 (Box 103)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973 (Box 103)
  - 1974, Jan.-Apr., 3 folders (Box 103)
  - 1974, May-Dec., 2 folders (Box 104)
  - Engagements Pending, 1974 (Box 104)
  - Engagements Declined, 1974 (Box 104)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974 (Box 104)
  - 1975, Jan.-May (Box 104)
  - 1975, June-Dec., 2 folders (Box 105)
  - Engagements Pending, 1975 (Box 105)
  - Engagements Declined, 1975 (Box 105)
  - 1976, Jan.-Aug. (Box 105)
  - 1976, Sept.-Dec. (Box 106)
  - Engagements Pending, 1976 (Box 106)
  - Engagements Declined, 1976 (Box 106)
  - 1977, Jan.-Dec., 3 folders (Box 106)
  - Engagements Pending, 1977 (Box 107)
  - Engagements Declined, 1977 (Box 107)
  - 1978, Jan- Dec., 3 folders (Box 107)
  - Engagements Pending and Itinerary, 1978 (Box 107)
  - Engagements Declined, 1978 (Box 107)
  - Engagements Pending prior to Marney's death, 1979 (Box 107)
  - Engagements Declined, 1979 (Box 107)
  - Engagements Pending prior to Marney's death, 1980 (Box 107)
- Subject Files Series, 1948-1978
  Alphabetically-arranged files for miscellaneous topics and organizations. Chiefly non-correspondence, including a wide variety of printed, mimeographed, and typed materials, such as reports, course materials, minutes, contracts, publicity items, financial statements, working papers, lists, original music scores, and biographical and personal information about Marney and his family.
  - Abingdon Press, 1949-1970and undated (Box 108)
  - American Baptist Convention, 1964-1966, July, 3 folders (Box 108)
  - American Baptist Convention, 1966, Aug.-Dec. (Box 109)
  - American National Red Cross: Mecklenburg County Chapter, 1964-1967 (Box 109)
  - Biographical Information, 1954-1978 (Box 109)
  - Boy Scouts of America: Mecklenburg County Council, 1962-1967and undated, 2 folders (Box 109)
  - Camping, Inc., 1960 (Box 110)
  - The Christian Century Foundation, 1959-1977and undated, 2 folders (Box 110)
  - Course Materials, 1954-1976and undated, 2 folders (Box 110)
  - Diary: Korea- Japan, 1954 (Box 111)
  - East Harlem Protestant Parish, 1958-1961 (Box 111)
  - Family History- Marney, 1971and undated (Box 111)
  - First Baptist Church, Austin, 1948-1961and undated (Box 111)
  - Founding Church of Scientology, 1971and undated (Box 111)
  - Georgia United Methodist Pastor's School, 1973 (Box 111)
  - Interpreters' House, 1968-1975 (Box 111)
  - Interracial Cooperation Committee: Mecklenburg Baptist Association, 1964-1965 (Box 111)
  - Myers Park Baptist Church, 1958-1967 (Box 111)
  - Myers Park Baptist Church: Deacon Work Sheet, 1963 (Box 111)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1962, Feb. 20 (Box 111)
  - North American Conference on Faith and Order, 1957, Sept.3-10 (Box 111)
  - Patrick Air Force Base, Fla., 1959, Mar. 18 (Box 111)
  - Peal, M.E., undated (Box 111)
  - Periodicals-Subscriptions, 1961-1965 (Box 111)
  - Property, Sharon Road, 1965 (Box 111)
  - Publicity: General, 1959-1971and undated (Box 112)
  - Publicity: Austin Texas, 1949-1965and undated (Box 112)
  - Publicity: Friends and Family, 1959-1972and undated (Box 112)
  - Publicity: Kentucky, 1948-1953and undated (Box 112)
  - Publicity: Myers Park Baptist Church, 1954-1966and undated (Box 112)
  - Salvation Army, Charlotte, NC 1962 (Box 112)
  - South Carolina Conference Pastors' School, 1974 (Box 112)
  - Southern Baptist Theological Seminary, 1958 (Box 112)
  - Theological Discussion Group,9 1961 (Box 112)
- Calendars Series, 1958-1979
  Two categories: spiral appointment calendars and flat desk calendars, each chronologically arranged. There are two copies of most of the flat calendars (a copy for Marney and one for his secretary, Edna Alsdurf). Notations on these calendars vary somewhat.
  - Spiral appointment calendars, 1958-1975 (Box 113)
  - Spiral appointment calendars, 1976-1978 (Box 114)
  - Flat desk calendars, 1963-1979, 3 folders (Box 114)
- Presidents National Advistory Commissions on Rural Poverty Series, 1965-1969 and undated
  Primarily mimeographed preliminary reports and other items, such as memoranda, minutes, statements, and correspondence. Chronological arrangement.
  - 1965-1967, July, 2 folders (Box 115)
  - 1969, July (Chap. 1-13, 2 folders) (Box 115)
  - 1969, July-Aug. (Box 115)
  - 1969, Aug.(Chap. 4-7) (Box 115)
  - 1969, Aug.(Chap. 8-11) (Box 116)
  - 1969, Aug.-Sept., 4 folders (Box 116)
  - undated, 3 folders (Box 116)
  - General Outline of Study, n.d (Box 116)
  - General Outline of Study, undated (Box 117)
- Southern Baptist Theological Seminary Series, 1899-1952 and undated, bulk, 1941-1944
  Lecture and course outlines, quiz questions, lesson assignments, reading lessons, charts, maps, and notes. These chiefly undated items are arranged by topic or name of course. Includes mimeographed, typed, and handwritten items. A few items are for Elizabeth Marney.
  - Christian Sociology, undated (Box 118)
  - Church History 71, undated, 2 folders (Box 118)
  - Course of Christian Missions, n d. (Box 118)
  - Exegetical Studies, 1941-1942 (Box 118)
  - Graduate Outlines in English New Testament: Epistles, undated (Box 118)
  - Graduate Outlines in English New Testament: Gospels, undated (Box 118)
  - Graduate Outlines in English New Testament: Interbibical Period, undated (Box 119)
  - Greek New Testament, undated (Box 119)
  - Ignatius, 1944, 3 folders (Box 119)
  - Maps, undated (Box 119)
  - Missionary Education (Elizabeth Marney), undated (Box 119)
  - Missions, 1899-1904 (Box 119)
  - Missions 51, undated (Box 119)
  - New Testament, undated (Box 120)
  - New Testament 32, undated, 2 folders (Box 120)
  - New Testament 35, undated (Box 120)
  - New Testament 36, undated (Box 120)
  - Old Testament 101, 1952, 2 folders (Box 120)
  - Old Testament Notebook: first-third quarters, undated, 3 folders (Box 120)
  - Report on Graduate Work, 1941-1944 (Box 121)
  - Theology 41: 1941-1942, 4 folders (Box 121)
  - Miscellaneous, 1941-1944and undated, 2 folders (Box 121)
- Notes Series, 1954-1959 and undated
  Chiefly Marney's reading notes and some outlines and notes that appear to be for publications, lectures, sermons, and devotionals. Mostly card size format of miscellaneous, undated documents.
  - 1954-1959 (Box 122)
  - Definitions of Materialism and Basic Assumptions, undated (Box 122)
  - Notes from Northrop: The Meeting of East and West, undated (Box 122)
  - Notes from Reid: Man and Christ, undated (Box 122)
  - Notes from Reichenback: The Rise of Scientific Philosophy, undated (Box 122)
  - Notes from Tillich: Love, Power, and Justice, undated, 2 folders (Box 122)
  - Notes from Titus: Living Issues in Philosophy, undated (Box 122)
  - Notes from Toynbee: A Study of History, undated (Box 123)
  - Notes from Troeltsch, undated, 2 folders (Box 123)
  - Notes from Whitehead: The Aims of Education, undated (Box 123)
  - Notes from Whitehead: Science and the Modern World, undated (Box 123)
  - undated (Box 123)
  - undated, 6 folders (Box 124)
  - undated, 5 folders (Box 125)
  - undated, 5 folders (Box 126)
  - undated, 5 folders (Box 127)
  - undated, 5 folders (Box 128)
  - undated, 5 folders (Box 129)
  - undated (Box 130)
- Printed Materials Series, 1946-1978
  Chronologically-arranged miscellaneous items, including newsletters, reports, leaflets, pamphlets, bulletins, programs, press releases, minutes, and bibliographies.
  - 1946-1978 and undated, 4 folders (Box 131)
- Miscellaneous Series, 1949-1978
  Three chronologically-arranged categories: pictures, clippings, and general. Clippings are from newspapers, bulletins, books, and periodicals and journals.
  - Clippings, 1949-1978 and undated (Box 131)
  - Pictures, 1954-1978 and undated (Box 131)
  - Pictures, undated, 2 folders (Box 132)
  - General, 1951-1978 and undated (Box 132)
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 1959-1978 and undated
  Three categories, with recordings listed alphabetically by author: cassette tapes, reel-to-reel tapes, and a few motion picture films. Chiefly works of Marney, such as sermons. Originals are closed to use. Preservation copies for many recordings are available in the collection. See individual listings. Technical Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed; please contact Research Services staff before coming to use the collection. Note: sound quality on some recordings is poor.
  - Cassette Tapes
    Conditions Governing Access note
    [ORIGINALS ARE CLOSED TO USE. Preservation copies on CD-ROM for many recordings have been made, but Technical Services staff need to produce listening copies before contents can be accessed; please contact Research Services staff before coming to use the collection. See individual listings for which originals have preservation copies made. Note: sound quality on some recordings is poor.]
    - Baum, Fr. Gregory, Birth of a New Spirituality, n. d. (Box 133, Item C-1)
    - Buttrick, Series of three lectures, 1977 (Box 133, Item C2-3)
    - Dickson, Lecture, Beyond the Denomination, n. d. (Box 134, Item C40)
    - Fletcher, John, Report: INTER-MET: Bold Venture in Theological Education, n. d. (Box 133, Item C4)
    - Gatu, John and Bruce Marsh, Personal and Indigenous Faith, n. d. (Box 133, Item C1)
    - Herzog, Fredrick, et al., Liberation Theology, n. d. (also see reel-to-reel listing). (Box 133, Item C5)
    - Howe, Revel L., Lecture: The Future of Ministry, undated (Box 133, Item C4)
    - Johnson, Robert Clyde, Reflections on Christology, 1971. (Box 133, Item C6)
    - Reck, Leander E., Jackson Lecture, 1978. (Box 133, Item C7-9)
    - Rendrick, Bruce, Institute Lectures, 1971, July 12-15. (Box 133, Item C10-12)
    - Kuhn, Maggie, The Church in Ministry with Older Adults, n. d. (Box 133, Item C5)
    - Marney, Carlyle, The Answering One, 1975, June2. (Box 133, Item C13)
    - Beyond Our Time and Place, 1975. (Box 133, Item C14-17)
    - Beyond the Denomination (Dickson-Marney lecture series), 1974, Apr. 11. (Box 133, Item C18)
    - Call to Change, n. d. (Box 133, Item Cl9)
    - The Carpenter's Son, 1965, July 12-15. (Box 133, Item C20-23)
    - The Christian Adventure, 1974, July 2-5. (Box 133, Item C24-27)
    - The Coming Faith, 1968, July 2-5. (Box 134, Item C28-31)
    - Conversion, 1977, Aug 21. (Box 134, Item C32)
    - Easter Service, 1977, Apr. 14. (Box 134, Item C33)
    - Eulogy for Dr. Blake Smith, n. d. (Box 134, Item C34)
    - Fundamentals of Relational Ministry, 1976. (Box 134, Item C35-38)
    - God No More in Zion, 1976. (Box 134, Item C39)
    - Interpreter's House: A Way Station for Understanding, 1974. (Box 134, Item C40)
    - Marney and Murdo McDonald discussions, 1973, Mar. (Box 134, Item C41-44)
    - Menninger Interview, 1977, Oct. 18. (Box 134, Item C45)
    - Monday with Clergy, n. d. (Box 134, Item C46-47)
    - Not to Condemn, 1977, Aug. 21. (Box 134, Item C32)
    - Peyton Lectures, 1978. (Box 134, Item C48-50)
    - The Real Issues, (Dickson-Marney lecture series), 1974, Apr. 12. (Box 134, Item C51)
    - The Recovery of a Person, 1962, July 10-13. (Box 134, Item C52-55)
    - The return of the Presence, 1971, July 5-9. (Box 134, Item C56-58)
    - The return of the Presence, 1971, July 5-9. (Box 135, Item C59)
    - The return of the Presence, 1971, July 12-15. (Box 135, Item C60-63)
    - Revelation as Conversation and Revolution, 1964, Sept. 17-18. (Box 135, Item C63-67)
    - This Twentieth Century, n. d. (Box 135, Item C68)
    - Twilight--Man's Disillusion, 1967, Sept. 27. (Box 135, Item C69)
    - Miscellaneous lectures and sermons, n. d. (Box 135, Item C70-71)
    - Marneyand panel - covenant, 1977, Aug. 12. (Box 135, Item C72)
    - An Ethic of Parsimony, 1977, Aug. 19. (Box 135, Item C73)
    - Incarnation, 1977, Aug. 15. (Box 135, Item C74)
    - Marsh, Bruce and John Gatu, Personal and Indigenous Faith, n. d. (Box 133, Item C1)
    - Mills, Edgar W., Interview: Clergy Career Stress, n. d. (Box 133, Item C4)
    - Muehl, William, Keeping God at Mind's Length, n. d. (Box 133, Item C6)
    - Randall, Claire, Fondren Lectures, 1978. (Box 135, Item C75-78)
    - Rouch, Mark A., Competent Ministry, 1974. (Box 134, Item C40)
    - Competent Ministry, n. d. (Box 133, Item C1)
    - Sanders, James A., An Invitation to the Dispossessed, n. d. (Box 133, Item C5)
    - Shea, Fr. John, Pathways to the Sacred, n. d. (Box 133, Item C1)
    - Simon, Series of three lectures, 1977. (Box 133, Item C3)
    - Stuart, The Word Became Flesh, n. d. (Box 135, Item C79)
    - Webber, George W., Analysis: New Dimensions of Vocation, n. d. (Box 133, Item C4)
    - Anonymous, His Face, like a Flint (also includes various kinds of music), 1974, Mar. 3. (Box 135, Item C80)
    - Anonymous, Memorial Service (also includes Requiem in C minor--Luigi Cherubini), 1974, May 26. (Box 135, Item C81)
    - Anonymous, Sermon: God Reconciling (atonement) 1974, Jan. 27. (Box 135, Item C82)
    - Anonymous, The Shape of Love, 1975, Mar. 16. (Box 135, Item C83)
    - Anonymous, Soundings II - American Baptist Convention, 1971, Oct. (Box 135, Item C84)
    - Anonymous, Untitled, 1974, Mar. 10. (Box 135, Item C85)
    - Anonymous, Miscellaneous tapes, n. d. (Box 135, Item C86-87)
  - Reel-to-reel Tapes
    [Originals closed to use. Listening copies for some reels are available in the collection in Box 146. See individual listings. Otherwise, Technical Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed. Please contact Research Services staff before coming to use the collection.]
    - Berry, James, Title unknown, 1972, Aug. 27. (Box 136, Item R2)
    - Docherty, George, Neglected Opportunity, 1967. (Box 136, Item R3)
    - Herzog, Frederick, God is Dead Debate/Discussion, 1966, June. Includes Marney. (Box 136, Item R1)
    - Challenges in Education, undated (see also cassette listings). (Box 136, Item R4)
    - Holcomb and Staff, Untitled, n. d. (Box 141, Item R73)
    - Hudson, W. Jack, Sermon "against" Marney in reply to newspaper story, 1968, Jan.2. (Box 140, Item R5)
    - James, Ralph, God is Dead Debate/Discussion, 1966, June. (Box 141, Item R1)
    - Macquarrie, John, Lecture by John Macquarrie, 1966, Feb. (Box 138, Item R1)
    - Marney, Carlyle, Christmas Service CBS TV, 1965, Dec. 24. (Box 140, Item R62-63)
    - Doctrine of Man (Bible Study on Gen. 1-11, series of six lectures), 1960. (Box 136, Item R6-8)